我一直知道有这么个人
I always knew she was out there.
我的真命天女
Right woman for me.
知道我们能组成家庭
Knew we'd start a family.
知道我会爱孩子胜过爱自己
Knew I'd love my kids more than myself.
从没想到我还有第二次机会
Never thought I'd get a second chance to try.
你和我这种人
Guys like you and me,
注定不能拥有家庭
we aren't meant to have families.
我们没有第二次机会
We don't get second chances.
怎么了
What?
我伤了你的心吗
Did I hurt your feelings?
我们把这事干完吧
Let's just get this over with.
现在没有退路了
No turning back now.
生活真好
What a life.
去他妈的生活
To hell with life.
我想要他们的现金
I want their cash.
你确定在里面吗
You sure it's in there?
我确定
I'm sure.
我们拿上钱就走人
We grab it and go.
不能有目击证人  记得吗
And no witnesses, remember?
天呐
Oh, my God.
格蕾茜
Gracie!
你们干什么
What are you doing?
上周你在哈德逊磨坊卖了价值五十万的小麦
You sold $1/2 million worth of grain at Hudson Mill last week.
我们要那笔钱
We want the money.
不在我这里
I don't have it.
票据证明你拿回家了一半现金
Scale ticket says you took home 50% in cash.
所以我再问一次  钱呢
So I'll ask you again. Where is it?
-怎么回事  -埃里克  我来处理
- What the hell's going on? - Eric, let me handle this.
你想帮你爸爸吗
You want to help your father out?
告诉我他办公室在哪
Tell me where his office is.
在楼上  但我告诉你
It's upstairs, but I'm telling you,
上面什么也没有
there is nothing up there.
带我去
Show me.
-爸爸  -快
- Daddy! - Come on.
-你也是  逞英雄的男孩  -爸爸
- You too, hero boy. - Daddy!
我们走
Let's go!
快
Come on!
你瞧  没有现金
See? No cash.
钱在哪
Where is it?
我说了  钱不在我这里
I told you, I don't have it.
不要
No!
你瞧  骗我的下场就是这个
See what happens when you lie to me?
他藏到哪里去了
Where is he hiding it?
我不知道  我发誓
I-I don't know! I-I swear!
住口  让她别哭了  知道吗
Stop! Make her stop crying, okay?
没事的
It's okay.
-你答应了我有现金  -没关系  没关系
- You promised me cash. - It's okay. It's okay.
我听说这里有钱
I was told there was money here.
在哪里  贱人
Where is it, bitch?
我不知道  我不知道
I don't know! I don't know!
是杰克在管理一切
Jack handled all of that.
那对你来说太糟了
Too bad for you, then.
别  她还是个孩子
Hey! Come on, she's just a kid.
我不在乎  你知道规矩
I don't care! You know the rules.
求你了  求你了
Please! Please.
我知道农场生意账户的密码
I know the password to the farm's business account.
里面至少有五十万
There's at least $1/2 million in there.
我可以用我的笔记本电脑转账
I can make a transfer on my laptop
然后  然后明天取钱给你们
and--and get it from the bank in the morning.
电脑就在那
It--it's right there!
不能在这  拿走笔记本
Not here. Get the laptop.
你们跟我们一起走
You're coming with us.
快
Come on!
不
No!
联邦调查局
通缉要犯部
第二季  第六集
好消息  我的房东保证
Good news: my landlord promises
一周内修好公寓的漏水
to fix the leak in my apartment in one week.
坏消息  换成纽约地产的时间
Bad news: in New York real estate time,
那就是至少一个月
that's a month minimum.
但谢谢你让我暂住在这  哈娜
But thanks for letting me crash here, Hana.
不客气  你的其他东西呢
No worries. Where's all your stuff?
都在这
Right here.
你有洗衣机和烘干机吧
You have a washer and dryer, right?
真的假的
Seriously?
你把脏衣服拿来了
You brought your laundry?
对  还带了这个
Yeah. And I brought this.
走一个庆祝下
Celebratory shot?
下班后吧
Maybe after work.
你是谁
Who are you?
泽蒂  这是克罗斯比  我们的新室友
Zadie, meet Crosby, our new roommate.
我错过家庭会议了吗
Did I miss a house meeting?
我们应该一起商量这种事
We're supposed to discuss these things.
只是暂时的
It's only temporary.
我的公寓水管漏了
I have a plumbing issue in my apartment.
欢迎
Welcome.
别碰我的果汁架
Don't touch my juice shelf.
好的
Okay.
今早六点
6:00 A.M. this morning,
工头到达宾夕法尼亚州萨默塞特的欣欣草农场后
foreman arrives at Rushing Meadow Farm in Somerset, Pennsylvania,
发现农场主的房门被闯入
and finds the front door of the owner's house broken into.
他进去后发现了这个
He goes inside to find this.
受害者是杰克·卡特莱特  事业小成的
Victims are Jack Cartwright, very successful
农场所有者  还有他十七岁的儿子埃里克
proprietor of the farm, and his 17-year-old son, Eric.
桌子被人翻遍了
That desk has been ransacked.
可能是有人在找钱
Could be someone was looking for money.
为了拿到钱把他俩都杀了
And murdered them both to get it.
还有
There's more.
埃里克是杰克前妻的儿子
Eric is Jack's son from his first marriage.
八年前  杰克二婚娶了艾米莉亚
Eight years ago, Jack then remarried Amelia,
新罕布什尔州的一位老师
a schoolteacher from New Hampshire.
她领养了埃里克  然后他们
She adopted Eric, and then they had
有了一个六岁的女儿格蕾茜
a six-year-old daughter named Gracie.
妈妈和女儿都失踪了
Both the mom and the daughter are missing.
所以入室抢劫变成了谋杀案
So it's a home invasion turned double murder
又变成了绑架案
turned double kidnapping?
正解
Correct.
我们要找的是这个人
And this is who we're looking for:
联调局通缉犯
萨缪·拉特利奇
萨缪·拉特利奇  38岁
Samuel Rutledge, 38 years old,
最近刚假释  之前坐了九年牢
recently paroled after serving nine years
因严重伤害罪
on an aggravated assault charge
被关在康科德的州男子监狱
at the State Prison for Men in Concord.
萨默塞特警局发现他的脚环被劈成了两半
Somerset PD found his ankle bracelet with the strap cut in two
扔在了离卡特莱特家五英里的车道上
five miles from the Cartwrights' driveway.
然后一小时前  一家纳舒厄的
Then about an hour ago, surveillance cam
加油站监控拍到了这个
at a gas station in Nashua caught this.
坐在副驾驶的是萨姆
That's Sam in the passenger seat.
他的搭档是谁
Who's his partner?
是货车车主
That's the owner of that van,
另一个正在假释的罪犯  彼得·提蒙斯
another ex-con on parole named Peter Timmons.
彼得·提蒙斯
他在曼彻斯特的格林斯博罗监狱
He did five years at Greensboro Correctional
因毒品罪坐了五年牢
in Manchester on a drug charge.
等等  他们不是同一个监狱的吗
Wait, they weren't in prison together?
不是
No.
我们只知道  他们都在新罕布什尔州
All we know is, they were in New Hampshire,
他们开了492英里  跨越五个州犯下了这些罪
they drove 492 miles through five states to commit these crimes,
现在正在回去
and now they're on their way back.
为什么袭击这家人
So why target this family?
为什么杀了两人  绑架妈妈和女儿
Why kill the two men, take the mom and daughter?
或许他们没拿到想要的
Maybe they didn't get what they wanted.
艾米莉亚和格蕾茜可能是连带伤害
Amelia and Gracie could be collateral.
她们也可能是人体盾牌
They could also be human shields.
安珀紧急通告发出了吗
Amber alert go out?
发了  还有针对小货车的协查通告
Yes, and a BOLO on the van.
我找到两人之间的联系了
Okay, I found their connection.
脚环上的监控器
The monitor on that ankle bracelet
追溯到一名叫巴里·桑兹的假释官
traces to a parole officer named Barry Sands.
巴里·桑兹
据新罕布什尔州狱政局回复
According to the New Hampshire DOC,
他们两个都在被他监管
he was supervising the both of them.
很好  桑兹的位置在哪儿
Excellent. Where is Sands' location?
康科德
康科德  与彼得最后的已知位置相同
Concord, same as Peter's last known.
萨姆的情况我没有看到
I'm not seeing anything for Sam.
我们分头行动
Okay, let's split it up.
巴恩斯和我去找假释官
Barnes and I will talk to the parole officer.
克罗斯比  你去彼得的住处查查
Crosby, check out Peter's apartment.
哈娜  追踪鉴证的反馈
Hana, follow up with Forensics.
确保他们勘验现场时收集了触碰DNA
Make sure they're processing the scene for touch DNA.
艾米莉亚和格蕾茜也就是一时对他们有用
Amelia and Gracie are only useful to these two until they're not.
联邦调查局通缉令  萨缪·拉特利奇
联邦调查局通缉令  彼得·提蒙斯
一旦她们失去了用处  两个人就都会死了
Soon as that happens, they're both dead.
毁坏卫星定位监控器在本州是重罪
Tampering with a GPS monitor is a felony in this state.
萨姆面临再被关上三年的刑罚
Sam's looking at another three years in lockup.
新罕布什尔州  康科德
这对现在的他来说还算轻的
Well, I'm guessing that's the least of his worries,
毕竟还有凶杀和双人绑架呢
given the murders and the double abduction.
你确定彼得和他一起干的吗
You sure Peter was with him?
对
Yes.
还真不知道他们俩是哥们儿
Didn't know they were pals.
他们俩每周和你的会面时间是一样的吗
Were their appointments at the same time each week?
对  每周二
Yeah, every Tuesday.
萨姆4点  彼得4点半
Sam at 4:00, Peter at 4:30.
逃犯在你的等待室会面
Our fugitives met in your waiting room.
萨姆是我们所谓的NH
Sam is what we call an NH,
"没有人性"
"Not human."
如果系统把你标记为魔鬼
If the system writes you off as a monster,
为什么还费劲去扮演其他角色呢
why bother acting like anything else?
彼得呢
And Peter?
从来都不暴力
Never violent,
他老婆给狱中的他送达离婚文件时他都没有
not even when his wife served him divorce papers in prison.
他有个前妻
He has an ex-wife?
琳达·卡罗尔
Linda Carroll.
和一个搞房地产的有钱人再婚了
Remarried some wealthy real estate guy.
但彼得在狱里信了教
But Peter found religion in prison.
他宽恕了她
He forgave her.
希望能重新建立个家庭  洗心革面开始新生活
Wanted to start a new family, a new life on the up-and-up.
如果彼得希望能重新来过
So if Peter wanted a second chance,
为什么他要把一切都搭上去帮助萨姆
why would he risk everything to help Sam?
爱  性  钱  或者是作伴
Love, sex, money, or sport.
我们没有萨姆的住址
We don't have an address for Sam.
他才出来6周
He's only been out six weeks.
一直在393号公路上的布拉沃汽车旅馆住
Been staying at the Bravo Motel off of 393.
我的客户都喜欢住在那里
Popular place for my clientele.
新鲜出炉的披萨
按您的要求定制
刚和这的经理谈过
Just spoke to the manager.
萨姆周一付了一周的房钱
Sam paid for a week in the room on Monday,
她之后就没见过他
and she hasn't seen him since.
卫生间有洗漱用品
There's toiletries in the bathroom
衣柜里挂着衬衣
and shirts hanging in the closet.
我的推测是  他计划着要回来的
My guess is, he's planning on coming back.
这是什么
What do we got here?
名牌手袋
Designer bag.
公主方切割的3克拉钻戒
Three-carat princess cut.
脚上穿的是大概800块的意大利皮鞋
About 800 bucks of Italian leather on her feet.
这女人绝对不吝惜钱
This woman is not hurting for cash.
这些不是抓拍的照片
These aren't candid photos.
又是个有钱的妇女和她的孩子
Another rich lady and her kid.
把照片发给哈娜
Send them to Hana.
让她运行人脸识别
Have her run face recognition.
我联系一下克罗斯比
I'm gonna check in with Crosby.
你在彼得的住处有什么发现
What'd you find at Peter's apartment?
这边没有迹象显示他认识受害人
Nothing here says this guy knew the victims
或者为什么他把他们作为目标
or why he was targeting them.
你那边有什么发现吗
You got anything?
我们在萨姆旅馆的房间找到了一些照片
Yeah, we found some photos in Sam's motel room,
是监视照片
surveillance pictures.
不管这个女的是什么人
Whoever this woman is,
他们绝对是在跟踪她
they're definitely stalking her.
让我看看
Let me see.
看看这个
Check this out.
是她
That's her.
绝对是同一个人
That's definitely the same woman.
看着是这样  她是谁
Sure looks like it. Who is she?
琳达·卡罗尔  彼得的前妻
Linda Carroll, Peter's ex-wife.
所以他们要回康科德来
That's why they're coming back to Concord.
她是他们的下一个目标
She's their next target.
他在干什么
What's he doing?
没事的啊
Shh. It's gonna be okay.
你转账了吗
You make the transfer?
转了  不过要两个小时才能过去
Yes, but it's gonna take a couple of hours to go through.
-不能接受  -求求你
- Not acceptable! - Please!
你从没说过要花两个小时
You never said it would take two hours.
不是我的错
It's not my fault.
萨姆  不过是耽搁了一点时间
Hey, Sam, it's just a minor delay.
听着
Hey, listen, listen.
我们按计划去袭击琳达家
We hit Linda's place like we planned,
这事回头再处理
take care of this after.
很多钱呢  值得等等
It's a lot of money. It's worth the wait.
上车里去
Get in the truck.
你要把我们带到哪儿
Where are you taking us?
闭上你的臭嘴  上车
Just shut your damn mouth and get in the truck.
上车
Get in!
快
Move.
你在哪儿偷的车
Where'd you steal the truck?
无所谓的  快点吧
Doesn't matter. Just hurry up.
一定是搞错了
There must be some mistake.
新罕布什尔州  彭布鲁克
彼得从不暴力
Peter's never been violent.
人在监狱会变的
Well, people do change in prison.
你是说他杀害了一个十来岁的孩子
So you're saying that he murdered a teenage boy
还有他的父亲
and his father too?
现在我们的重点是要找到他绑架的
Right now, our priority is to find the woman
那个女人和孩子
and the child that he abducted
以免一切都太晚了
before it's too late.
你有没有注意到最近
Are you aware that anybody
是不是在跟踪你
might've been following you recently?
没注意  怎么了
No. Why?
我们认为你和你的家人
Well, we think that you and your family
可能是彼得和萨姆的下一个目标
might be Peter and Sam's next target.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
我会在你家外面
I'll post officers outside your house
派警官来保护你们
to protect you, okay?
彼得出狱以后你见过他吗
Have you seen Peter since he got out of prison?
没有  但我们离婚以后
No, but we kept in regular correspondence
一直有通信
after our divorce.
他的假释官说他宽恕了你
Yeah, his parole officer said he forgave you?
是的
He did.
他希望我能往前走
He wanted me to move on.
我们婚礼那天  他给我和我丈夫
He wrote me and my husband
寄了一首写得很有感情的诗
a lovely poem on our wedding day
亨利出生时还给他写了一首
and one for Henry at his birth.
如果你不介意  我想看看
If you don't mind, I'd like to see those.
无论是什么事  你都可以告诉我
You know, whatever it is, you can tell me.
我在彼得的假释听证会上做过证
I testified at Peter's parole hearing.
我告诉假释委员会
I told the parole board
彼得绝对不会伤害任何人  而如今
that Peter would never hurt anyone, and--and now...
这都是我的错
This is my fault.
不  这不是你的错
No. This isn't your fault.
这是那两个暴徒的错
This is the fault of two violent men,
其中一个曾让你相信他们已经改过自新了
one that convinced you they'd been reformed.
看到他人的好的一面并没有错
It's not a bad thing to see the good in people.
有人把这个社区称为"美国梦"
Some people call this neighborhood the American Dream.
我叫它"美国谎言"
I call it the American Lie.
我要上厕所
I have to go to the bathroom.
憋着
Hold it!
但我真的必须要
But I really have to go.
别说了  亲爱的  会没事的
Shh, honey. It'll be okay.
我不喜欢带着累赘
I don't like having baggage.
我们就按计划行事  好吗
We just stick to the plan, okay?
我们就快成功了
We're almost there.
-趴下  -为什么
- Get on the floor. - What for?
做就是了
Just do it!
停车
Stop.
彼得
Well, Pete,
这就是我们所说的二振
this here is what we call strike two.
我不明白  他们怎么会
I don't understand. How did they--
没关系
It doesn't matter.
往后退  然后调头
Just back up and turn around
在他们看到我们前  慢慢转过去
nice and slow before they see us.
我开始觉得你和她们一样
I'm beginning to think you're just like them:
是个累赘  而远非有用的人
more of a liability than you are an asset.
你知道我会怎样处理累赘
And you know what I do with liabilities.
新罕布什尔州  拉科尼亚
还没人给我们打电话
Nobody called us about any ransom
索要艾米莉亚和格蕾茜的赎金  如果他们打了
for Amelia or Gracie, and if they did--
我们会想办法付钱的
we'd have found a way to pay it.
杰克或艾米莉亚提到过
Did Jack or Amelia mention seeing anyone
在过去几天看到了什么奇怪的人或事吗
or anything out of the ordinary these last few days?
你们不怎么跟你们的女儿说话吗
You don't talk to your daughter much?
艾米莉亚是个很难相处的孩子
Amelia was a challenging child.
我曾称她为我的小豪猪
I used to call her my little porcupine.
-她是个很漂亮的姑娘  -是的
- She was a beautiful girl. - Yes.
人们经常对她这样说
People were constantly telling her that.
然后在某个年纪  男孩子们蜂拥而来
Then at a certain age, the boys came swarming.
如果艾米莉亚没那么醉心于她的书本的话
Amelia could've had them wrapped around her finger
她本可以把他们玩弄于股掌之间
if she wasn't so wrapped up in her books.
她是个聪明的姑娘
She's a smart girl.
她六岁时就跟我说
She was only six years old, and she said to me,
"妈妈  我完全有能力为自己做饭"
"Mommy, I'm perfectly capable of making my own dinner."
所以我就让她做了
So I let her.
在一年级时就自力更生
Self-sufficient for a first grader.
酗酒者子女的共同特征
But a common trait in the children of alcoholics.
你戒酒
How long has it been
有多长时间了
since you put down the bottle?
我  我记不清有多少次
I-I can't count how many times
醉醺醺地开车送我女儿去上学
I drove my daughter to school drunk
或者扭得她肩膀脱臼
or dislocated her shoulder
或扭伤她的胳膊
or twisted her arm.
我并不以此为荣
I'm not proud of that.
你当时病了  亲爱的
You were sick, honey.
在她十六岁那天的夏天  艾米莉亚让我戒酒
Amelia asked me to quit drinking the summer she turned 16.
她说如果我爱她  我会戒的
Said if I loved her, I'd do it.
但你没有
But you didn't.
我戒不了
I couldn't do it,
哪怕是为了我的小女儿
even for my own little girl.
反正那个夏天没戒成
Not that summer, anyway.
我们当时在佛蒙特州的伊甸湖畔租了幢房子
We had rented a house on Lake Eden in Vermont.
然后就发生了意外
And then there was the accident.
什么意外
What accident?
艾米莉亚的朋友  柯林斯家的儿子
Amelia's friend, the Collins boy,
在桥上胡闹时摔了下去
he was horsing around on a bridge, took a bad fall.
她看到了整件事
She saw the whole thing.
从那以后艾米莉亚就不一样了
Amelia was never the same after that.
她得了抑郁症
She suffered from depression.
甚至在她嫁给杰克  并收养埃里克后
Even after she married Jack and adopted Eric,
也从未有过好转
never got any better...
直到他们有了格蕾茜
until they had Gracie.
做母亲改变了她吗
Motherhood changed her?
艾米莉亚成为了欢乐的化身
Amelia became joy personified.
她告诉我  "妈妈  我有了第二次机会
She said to me, "Mama, I've got a second chance.
我感觉自己好像重生了"
I feel like I've been reborn."
但后来艾米莉亚就变得艾米莉亚...
But then Amelia being Amelia...
出什么事了
What happened?
格蕾茜出生后他们搬到了宾夕法尼亚州
They moved to Pennsylvania after Gracie was born.
我们已经五年没见过她
We haven't seen her for five years--
或者我们的外孙女了
or our granddaughter.
他名叫大卫·柯林斯
His name is David Collins.
明星运动员在伊甸湖的事故中受伤
他从一座桥上跳水  入水姿势不对
He dived off a bridge, hit the water wrong,
双侧肩膀都摔骨折了
broke both his shoulders.
那一定很糟糕
It must've been awful.
而艾米莉亚目睹了整个过程吗
And Amelia saw the whole thing?
是的  这件事再加上她那酗酒的父亲
Yes, that, coupled with her alcoholic father,
让她的情况急剧恶化
sent her into a spiral.
她好多年都不跟她的家人说话
She hasn't spoken to her family for years,
甚至在她嫁人  格蕾茜出生以后
even after she got married and Gracie was born.
这个外孙女是个重归于好的机会
Well, the granddaughter was a chance at reconciliation,
然而她依然选择远离她的父母
yet she still chose to stay away from her parents.
你认为这事与他们有关吗
You think they're involved somehow?
他们似乎不会做这样的事
They don't seem right for that.
这案子不能按照常理推断
Nothing is right about this case.
彼得·提蒙斯是位非暴力的和平主义者
Peter Timmons is a nonviolent pacifist
他杀了两个人  然后盯上了
who murdered two people, then targeted his ex-wife
友好离婚的前妻
after an amicable divorce.
这与艾米莉亚没关系
There's no connection to Amelia,
所以我想唯一的动机是  钱
so the only motive I can think of is...money.
我刚接到匡提科市DNA检测部门的电话
I just got off the phone with the DNA unit at Quantico.
他们对艾米莉亚死去的丈夫和房间内发现的
They ran touch DNA on Amelia's dead husband
格蕾茜的小毯子做了接触性DNA检验
and Gracie's blankie they found at the house.
结果并不匹配
Not a match.
所以杰克不是生物学上的父亲吗
So Jack isn't the biological father?
-不是  -那是谁
- No. - Then who is?
如果我上传格蕾茜的DNA数据
If I upload Gracie's DNA profile,
我们可以从DNA联合索引系统开始
we can start with CODIS.
尽管希望不大  但这是个开始
I mean, it's a long shot, but it's a start.
彼得·提蒙斯  逮捕记录
巴里·桑兹
你找到匹配的人了吗
You get a match?
是的
Yeah.
他就在系统里  因为我们认识他
He's in the system because we know him.
格蕾茜的父亲是彼得·提蒙斯
Gracie's father is Peter Timmons.
DNA联合索引系统-819422  彼得·提蒙斯
格蕾茜·卡特莱特的DNA数据与在格林斯博罗服刑的
囚犯彼得·提蒙斯相吻合
这根本不是绑架
This isn't a kidnapping.
这是一家人在逃亡
This is a family on the run.
彼得·提蒙斯是我这里唯一一位
Peter Timmons was one of my only inmates
新罕布什尔州  曼彻斯特
不参与身体或语言冲突的囚犯
not to engage in physical or verbal conflict.
你这里大多是很暴力的罪犯吗
You have mostly violent criminals here?
是的
Yes.
哪怕是毒品罪犯  那些像彼得的人
Even the drug offenders, ones like Peter,
通常也会为了生存不得不变得很暴力
usually have to turn violent to survive.
但他从不参加吗
But he stayed above the fray?
他只关注他的未来
Focused on his future.
我们想看看彼得在这里时的来访记录
We'd like to see a log of Peter's visitors during his time here.
有什么特别关注的人吗
Anyone in particular?
艾米莉亚·卡特莱特
Amelia Cartwright?
你认识她吗
You know her?
对啊  艾米莉亚不是个访客
Yeah, Amelia wasn't a visitor.
她是我们创意写作课的老师
She was our creative writing teacher,
彼得在她那儿上课
and Peter was in her class--
一周两次上了三年
twice a week for three years.
他们待在一起的时间很长啊
That's a lot of time to spend together
在没有监管的情况下
without supervision.
彼得没有暴力倾向
Yeah, well, Peter wasn't violent.
如果他想做个情人而非斗士
And if he wanted to be a lover and not a fighter,
我完全可以理解
fine by me.
在这里的时候和艾米莉亚生了孩子
He fathered Amelia's child during his time here,
就是他们潜逃时带走的孩子
the same child they took on the run
在暴力犯罪之后
with a violent criminal.
我还以为他喜欢诗歌呢
I just thought he liked poetry.
彼得在艾米莉亚课上的时候
Was there a specific computer that Peter used
有没有用过一台特定的电脑
when he was in Amelia's writing class?
有  在实验室里  走这边
Yeah, in the lab. This way.
哪一台是彼得用的
Which one did Peter use?
他一直用最后一排的第二台
Second one in the back, always.
听我说  各位
Listen up, everyone.
放下你手头的工作  回避一下
Save your work, and let's clear out.
我祖母在1986年的时候也有这台电脑
My grandmother had this computer in, like, 1986.
给  监狱长给的彼得在监狱里用的邮箱和密码
Here, the warden gave us peter's prison email and password.
给当地报纸专栏的啰嗦稿件
Long-winded op-eds to local papers,
总编  罪犯也是人
给他前妻的辞藻华丽的信
flowery messages to his ex-wife.
我曾觉得我们的结合
"I once thought you and I were joined
琳达·卡罗尔  生日快乐
就像一棵老橡树的根部
Like the roots of an ancient oak.
我知道我们拥有的都已逝去
I know what we had was fleeting.
我们本是一根树枝上的两片树叶
We were two leaves on a single branch."
跟琳达·卡罗尔给我们的信上
That's the same poetic tone
诗歌的语气一样
as the letters Linda Carroll gave us.
但没有和艾米丽亚往来的邮件
But nothing to or from Amelia.
未找到发给或来自艾米莉亚·卡特莱特
除非它们从没被发出去
Unless they were never sent.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
这是个恐怖分子大概在2010年停用的把戏
It's a trick terrorists abandoned circa 2010.
你在草稿箱写一封邮件
You write an email in the drafts folder.
你给某人你的用户名让他登录
You give someone your username and log-in.
登录之后阅读并回复  但是邮件从未被发出过
They log in, read and respond, but the email never gets sent.
这样狱警就没法监控他们的联络
And prison staff can't monitor their correspondence.
但是我们可以
But we can.
彼得  艾米莉亚  彼得  艾米莉亚  这持续了多久
Peter, Amelia. Amelia, Peter. How long's this going for?
好多年
Years.
-萨姆  -你要干什么
- Sam. - What are you doing?
-嗨  -妈妈
- Hey. - Mom!
-你要带我去哪  -不要啊
- Where are you taking me? - No!
萨姆  等等
Sam, wait!
妈妈
Mama!
他们要带妈妈去哪里
Where are they taking Mommy?
你把钱转账了吗
Did you make the transfer?
我在努力  我在努力
I'm trying. I'm trying.
还在尝试
It's trying now.
没事的  格蕾茜
It's okay, Gracie.
我不会让你妈妈出任何事的
I won't let anything happen to your mom...
还有你
or you.
还在  还在  还在
It's--it's--it's--
求你了  求你了  求你了
Please, please, please, please, please.
-萨姆  -不要  不要
- Sam! - Please don't. Please don't.
格蕾茜  呆在这里
Gracie, stay here.
-求你了  求你了  -等等  等等
- Please, please don't. - Wait! Wait!
-求你  -喂
- Please. - Hey.
你别管
Stay out of it.
她说已经转账了  但是钱没有转过来
She said she made the transfer, but it didn't go through.
转账还没有被处理
No, it says it's still pending.
听着  那是很多钱
Look, it is a lot of money.
转账是需要时间的
It takes time for it to go through.
这你早就知道了
Which you knew.
现在太晚了
It's too late now.
今早本还可以解决
First thing this morning would've worked,
但是现在你是个失踪人口
but now you're a missing person
整个新英格兰都有找你的大头照
with your face plastered all over New England.
你走进一家银行会把我们俩都送进了监狱
You walk into that bank, it puts us both into jail.
你不能杀了她
You can't just shoot her.
她的孩子还在看
Her kid's watching.
下一个就轮到她
And she'll be next.
萨姆  不能这么做
Sam, this is a mistake.
你和这些女人有什么关系
What is it with you and these ladies, huh?
你跟她这样的贱人有一腿吗
You got a thing for bitches like her?
或者你是个恋童癖
Or is it kids that are your thing?
那边有个小女孩
There's a little girl in there.
纯洁的  未被触碰过
She's pure, untouched,
和她妈妈一样好看
nice looks like her mama.
我能解决这件事
I can fix this.
不一定非要是我去银行
I don't have to be the one to go into the bank.
我的父亲会去
My father will.
你父亲
Your father.
他住在康科德
He lives in Concord.
把我带到他家里
Take me to his house.
我会把钱转给他
I'll transfer him the money,
然后他会去银行把钱取出来
and he'll go in and pick it up.
然后一道把警察引过来
And bring the cops back with him.
他不会的
No, he won't.
如果我叫他不要这么做他就不会的
He won't, not if I tell him not to.
求你了  求你了
Please. Please.
这笔钱足够给你任何你想要的新开始
It is enough for any new beginning you want,
我会把它们全部给你
and I will give you every penny
只要你能放过我和我女儿
if you just let me and my daughter go.
求你了
Please.
我求求你
Please, I'm begging you.
彼得给艾米莉亚
From Peter to Amelia:
我见到你之前
"Before I met you,
我不能与他人共享灵魂
I could not fathom sharing my soul.
如今我必须如此  你我之灵魂相生相伴
Now I know I must, for your soul is its mate,
终将合一
and they must become one."
希望她会给这首诗打不及格
I hope she gave him a D on that.
艾米莉亚给彼得
From Amelia back to Peter:
"撑我度过这周的唯一动力
"The only thing that gets me through the week
就是知道我将见到你
is knowing I'll see you.
你是我的所有  我爱你"
You are my everything. I love you."
听起来很真诚
That actually sounds sincere.
是很真诚
It is sincere.
艾米莉亚脆弱而压抑
Amelia was vulnerable and depressed,
彼得是在趁虚而入
and Peter was taking advantage.
给她写信  引她上钩
Writing her letters, reeling her in.
你看见过我的镜片清洗剂吗
Have you seen my lens cleaner?
但是彼得是在监狱的人
But Peter is the one in prison.
他怎么会有主动权呢
How does that give him the upper hand?
可能是坏男孩症
Well, it could be hybristophilia.
在你拍档的犯罪案件中找到灵感了吗
Finding stimulation in your partner's crimes?
艾米莉亚被彼得吸引恰恰是因为他在监狱里
Amelia was attracted to Peter because he was in prison.
坏男孩综合症
Bad-boy syndrome.
这就是为什么很多连环杀手
It's why a lot of serial killers
能在监狱里结婚
get married in prison.
问题是  彼得一直没有暴力倾向
Problem is, Peter's never been violent.
你也没有啊
Neither have you.
我是说只要足够聪明
I'm just saying, there's plenty of ways
控制他人的方法有很多
to control people if you're smart.
是的
Right.
可能这就是彼得在做的
Maybe that's what Peter was doing.
他知道艾米莉亚婚姻不美满
He knew Amelia was unhappy in her marriage.
然后他俩有了孩子
Then they got pregnant.
等他出来  他就能利用那个
When he gets out, he can use that as leverage
来得到她丈夫的钱
to go after her husband's money.
通过把他除掉吗
By getting rid of him?
但彼得不是个杀手
But Peter's not a killer.
也许这就是萨姆的作用了
Maybe that's where Sam comes in.
他是打手  为了钱加进来
He's the muscle, in it for the money.
我可能找到答案了
I might have an answer on that.
是什么
What you got?
六个月前  彼得告诉艾米莉亚
Six months ago, Peter told Amelia
他贩毒时藏了一些现金
about some cash he had hidden away from his drug-dealing days.
她问他藏在哪  然后他说如果她也出一些
She asked where, and he said that he would tell her
他就告诉她
if she'd come up with some of her own.
给格蕾茜的储备金吗
Nest egg for Gracie?
上面没说  但艾米莉亚回复说
Doesn't say, but Amelia replied
如果她从账户上一次转走一点
that Jack probably wouldn't notice
杰克可能注意不到
if she skimmed some money off the accounts.
两周后  彼得用这个回复了她
Two weeks later, Peter replied with this.
发件人彼得  收件人艾米莉亚  44 49 89 -71 32 28
这些是什么  银行账户吗
What are these, bank accounts?
我觉得不是
I don't think so.
它们看上去更像是GPS坐标
They look more like GPS coordinates.
可能是个传统寻宝游戏
Could be a traditional geocache,
但没那些花哨的谜语暗语
no fancy word problems or riddles attached.
这是中途点
That's the waypoint.
是新罕布什尔州北部的一处森林
It's a forest in upstate New Hampshire.
他们有可能带格蕾茜去那
Where they could be headed with Gracie.
你和肯尼去看看
You and Kenny go check it out.
你觉得萨姆知道这事吗
You think Sam knows about this?
我不知道
I have no idea.
他可能都不知道彼得是格蕾茜她爸
He may not even know Peter is Gracie's father,
但一旦他发现了
but once he finds out,
情况可能会急剧恶化
this whole thing might get a lot worse.
没人在家
No one's home.
他们在里面
They're in there.
可能是在地下室看电视
You know, probably watching TV in the basement.
来  亲爱的
Come on, sweetie.
不行
No!
她留在这里
She stays here.
但我爸会想见她的
But my dad will want to see her.
不行
Not an option.
如果你试图逃走
And if you try to run--
我绝不会丢下我女儿
I would never leave my daughter.
那我们就没问题了
Then we won't have a problem.
没事的
It's okay.
跟着她
Go with her.
要是他们试图报警  你知道该怎么做
They try to call the cops, you know what to do.
走后门  别走前门
Use the back door, not the front.
搞什么
Hey. What the hell?
艾米莉亚  你要把你父母也牵扯进来吗
Amelia, you're bringing your parents into this?
别傻了
Don't be an idiot.
这不是他们家
This isn't their house.
那我们来这干什么
Then what are we doing here?
你刚向萨姆许诺了五十万美元现金
You just promised Sam $500,000 in cash!
反正他永远拿不到
Which he's never gonna get.
计划有变  彼得
The plan's changed, Peter.
从我们没拿到琳达的钱开始就变了
It started when we didn't get Linda's money.
我不知道警察会在那
Yeah, I didn't know the cops were gonna be there.
显然
Obviously.
我也不知道萨姆这么难搞
And I didn't know Sam was such a loose cannon.
所以我们一直随机应变
So we keep improvising.
而现在我们不用付他那一份了
And now we don't have to pay him his share.
好  棒极了
O-okay, great, yeah.
所以让我们别给萨姆钱
So let's not give Sam his money,
但把他和我们女儿一起留在车里
but let's leave him in the car with our daughter?
她甚至都不知道我是她爸
Who doesn't even know I'm her father.
我们会告诉她的
We're gonna tell her.
什么时候
When?
等我说可以了
When I say so. That's when.
你只要相信我就好
You just need to trust me.
现在  我们有更大的问题要解决
Right now, we've got a bigger problem.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你知道的
You know.
我从没杀过人
I've never killed anyone before.
你也从没像爱我一样爱一个人
And you've never loved anyone like me before.
所以
So...
如果你真的爱我
if you really love me...
我爱
I do.
证明给我看
Prove it.
她在哪
Where is she?
我要我妈咪
I want my mommy!
闭嘴坐好
Hey! Shut up and sit down!
我的天
Oh, my God.
我的天  我的天  我的天
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
累赘和有用的
Liabilities and assets.
你自己说的
You said it yourself.
邻居听到了枪声
Neighbor heard the gunshot
马上跑到窗边看
and ran to her window,
拍到了一辆福特皮卡
managed to get a photo of a Ford pickup
逃离现场
fleeing the scene.
查过车牌号了吗
You run the plates on that?
是韦伯斯特镇一家人的
Yeah, belongs to a family in Webster.
他们说那是他们孩子的车  他去上大学了
They said it's their kid's car. He's off at college.
他们都不知道车丢了
They didn't even know it was missing.
更新一下失窃车辆名单
Let's update the BOLO.
死者在这  大家让一下
DOA's over here. Let's make a hole, people.
斧柄上的指纹是彼得·提蒙斯的
Prints on the ax handle matched to Peter Timmons,
所以我们通知了你们
hence our phone call.
受害者身上没钱包也没身份证
No wallet or ID on the victim,
但我猜你们认识他
but I'm guessing you know him.
是你们的另一个逃犯  对吗
Your other fugitive, right?
对  萨姆·拉特利奇
Yeah, Sam Rutledge.
用斧子剖开腹部然后在胸部补了一枪
Gutted with an ax and then shot in the chest.
看来我们低估彼得了
I guess we underestimated Peter.
目击者说他们看到女人和小孩了吗
Did the witness say they saw a woman and a child?
你们的失踪人口吗  我还没问到那
Your missing persons? I hadn't gotten there yet.
你们来时我还在问她
I was still interviewing her when you rolled up.
我去问她
I'll go talk to her.
哈娜  什么事
Hana, what's up?
我们顺着那些GPS坐标
We followed those GPS coordinates
找到了他们藏东西的地方
to the nest egg.
是个旅行箱
It's some kind of steamer trunk.
我们到这里时已经被挖出来了
It was already dug up when we got here.
-里面有东西吗  -是空的
- Anything in it? - Empty.
但这里到处都是轮胎印
But there's tire tracks everywhere.
克罗斯比在检查比对  有人比我们先到
Crosby's off checking them out. Somebody beat us here.
杰斯
Jess?
可能是彼得和艾米莉亚
Probably Peter and Amelia.
他们杀了萨姆  丢下车
They killed Sam, ditched the van,
开了辆失窃的福特皮卡跑了
and took off in a stolen Ford pickup.
肯定还没跑远
Can't have gotten far.
我们该叫鉴识科的人过来
We should get ERT down here.
让他们看看这些轮胎印是不是那辆福特的
They can see if these tracks match that Ford.
也能检查一下这个箱子
They can also test this trunk.
埋得很深  但上面也可能有DNA
It was buried pretty deep, but it's probably full of DNA.
好  让他们查查看
Okay. Run it and see.
鉴识科说检查完旅行箱了
Tech said he's done with the steamer trunk.
-他把报告发过来了吗  -发了  收到了
- Did he send the report? - Yep. Got it.
"残存痕迹与美国货币一致"
"Trace elements consistent with U.S. currency."
所以之前里面确实有钱
So there was cash in there.
谁先拿到的  彼得还是艾米莉亚
Who got to it first, Peter or Amelia?
都不是
Neither.
上面的DNA是大卫·柯林斯的
DNA found belongs to David Collins.
样本  大卫·柯林斯
艾米莉亚的朋友
Amelia's friend,
桥上事故那个
the one from the accident on the bridge?
奇怪  他有案底吗
That's weird. Does he have a record?
他在一所私立学校当教练
He's a coach at a private school
麦卡锡  工作经历  高中  大卫  柯林斯
需要DNA和指纹
that requires DNA and prints.
艾米莉亚为什么要把她和彼得共有的
Why would Amelia give him the coordinates
存款的位置告诉他
to the nest egg she shared with Peter?
她自己随时都可以拿到
She could have gotten it anytime by herself.
能递给我一下彼得给他前妻的信吗
Can you pass me the letters that Peter sent to his ex-wife?
谢谢
Thank you.
大卫·柯林斯  艾米莉亚·卡特赖特  萨姆·拉特利奇
"我这儿的日子充满着嘈杂
"My days here are filled with noise.
铁窗哐当作响  脏水冲洗食盘
"Bars clanging. Slop hitting trays.
拳头落在身上
"Men's fists on flesh.
但是我充耳不闻
"But all I hear is the deafening silence
唯沉浸在让你失望的寂寂无声中"
"of having disappointed you."
这跟他写给艾米莉亚的狱中诗
That's a far cry from the prison poetry
大不一样
he sent Amelia.
不是彼得写的  艾米莉亚写的
Peter didn't write these. Amelia did.
她故意设计他的前妻
She was setting up the ex-wife,
让她以为彼得原谅她了
making her think Peter had forgiven her.
让她放松警惕
That way, she's an easier target.
你是说不是彼得主导的
You're saying Peter's not leading this?
他可能杀了萨姆
He might've killed Sam,
但是艾米莉亚在发号施令
but Amelia's calling the shots.
这和钱无关
This was never about the money.
而是艾米莉亚需要控制她生命中的男人
This is about Amelia's need to control the men in her life.
我们有大卫的地址吗
We have an address for David?
住在蒂尔顿  屋主是玛丽·柯林斯
Residence in Tilton owned by Mary Collins.
看来他和姐姐住在一起
Looks like he lives with his sister.
新罕布什尔州  蒂尔顿
玛丽·柯林斯
Mary Collins?
我是联调局的拉克鲁瓦探员
I'm Agent LaCroix of the FBI.
你们找到我弟弟了吗
Did you find my brother?
大卫  我们以为他住这里
David? We thought he lived here.
他是啊  但他不见了
He does, but he's disappeared.
他早上去上班
He went to work this morning,
但学校说他没出现过
but the school said he never showed.
我给他打了一个小时的电话
I've been calling his cell for an hour,
但他没接
and he's not answering.
怎么回事
What's going on?
我们在找一个女人  她被绑架了
We're looking for a woman who's been abducted.
我们觉得你弟弟也许卷入其中了
We think your brother might be involved.
艾米莉亚·卡特赖特
Amelia Cartwright?
那个艾米莉亚
That Amelia?
不可能
No way.
大卫绝不会伤害她
David would never hurt her.
他爱了她一辈子
He's been in love with her his whole life,
哪怕她那样对他
even after what she did to him.
桥上意外
The accident on the bridge?
那不是意外
It was no accident.
我们在伊甸湖边的房屋消暑
We were at our house out on Lake Eden for the summer.
我也在
I was there.
怎么回事
And what happened?
艾米莉亚怂恿他
Amelia was egging him on.
她对大卫说  如果他爱她
She told David if he loved her,
就跳下去证明给她看
he'd prove it and jump.
-她推了他  -她用不着
- She pushed him? - She didn't have to.
我弟弟一心只想着证明给她看
My brother was so obsessed with impressing her,
就决定跳下去
he decided to dive.
两个肩膀都撕裂了
Ripped both his shoulders apart
橄榄球前程也毁了
and ruined his football career,
都因为艾米莉亚
all because of Amelia.
也许他终于想报复了
Maybe he's finally looking for payback.
你不懂
You don't understand.
艾米莉亚对男人有魔力
Amelia has this power over men.
她对他们越差
It's like, the worse she treats them,
他们就越喜欢她
the more they like her.
很遗憾  她不见了  但是大卫不会绑架她
I'm sorry she's missing, but David wouldn't take her.
恐怕是他自己出去找她了
He's probably out looking for her himself.
好  谢谢你
All right. Well, thank you.
你家湖边的房子后来怎样了
Oh, whatever happened to your family house on the lake?
还是我们的  怎么了
We still own it. Why?
就是好奇  谢谢
Just curious. Thanks.
祝新的开始
To fresh starts.
没钱怎么重新开始
How do we start fresh without money?
别担心
Don't worry.
我已经搞定了
I got this covered.
妈妈  过来看
Hey, Mom, come and check this out.
是什么
Oh, what is it?
你要给我看什么
What you got?
我给动物们做了一个家
I'm making a house for the animals.
好有意思
How fun.
小篝火
Little campfire?
真好
So good.
有意思  对吗
Having fun, right?
格蕾茜
Gracie.
你妈和我想告诉你一件事
There's something your mother and I wanna tell you.
别现在
Not now.
带格蕾茜进去
Take Gracie inside.
我来处理这里
I'll take care of this.
放松  熊爸爸
Relax, Papa Bear.
我们开始新生活需要的东西
Everything we need to start a new life
都在那辆车上
is in that car.
他是谁
Who is he?
一个老朋友
An old friend.
这是他家
This is his place.
佛蒙特州伊甸草地巷49号
49 Meadow Lane, Eden, Vermont.
我们现在过来
On our way now.
好
All right.
艾米莉亚为什么要回到事故地点
Why would Amelia go back to the scene of the accident?
她这种心理变态类型
Her brand of psychopathy
需要通过重塑才能活
requires reinvention to survive,
而重塑需要切断所有过去的联系
and reinvention requires cutting all ties to the past.
回到湖边的房子
Isn't going back to the lake house
不是背道而驰吗
the opposite of that?
如果她是回去洗清原罪就不算
Not if she's returning to cleanse her original sin.
首先她处理了丈夫和继子
First she took care of the husband and the stepson.
然后是萨姆  但她不认识他
And Sam, but she didn't know him.
彼得呢
What about Peter?
取决于他还有没有用
Mm, depends if he's still useful or not.
作恶者变成了受害者
The perpetrator becomes the victim.
不知道大卫·柯林斯是不是也是这样
Wonder if the same holds true for David Collins.
对艾米莉亚  一切皆有可能
With Amelia, anything's possible.
照你说的  三本护照
Three passports, as requested.
飞机票呢
Plane tickets?
没有引渡
No extradition.
你忘了什么东西吧
Think you're forgetting something.
给你的吗  不可能忘记
For you? No way.
树下箱子里的七万五千元
75K from the trunk under the tree.
真难挖啊  顺便说一句
Which was a pain to dig up, by the way.
他怎么知道存款的
How does he know about the nest egg?
如果我们要去挖那口箱子
If we'd gone to dig up that trunk,
我俩现在已经穿着橙色囚衣了
we'd both be in orange jumpsuits by now.
我更喜欢绿色
I prefer green.
你那份  一万元
Your cut. Ten grand.
说好的是两万
Deal was 20.
事前一万  事后一万
Ten before, ten after.
什么尾款
After what?
我渴了
I'm thirsty.
好  你带她去吧
Go on. Take her.
走吧  格蕾茜
Come on, Gracie.
你准备好了吗
You ready to do this?
如果你希望我做的话
If you really want me to.
都在计划之中
All part of the plan.
然后我们在去机场的路上顺路去银行
Then we stop by the bank on the way to the airport.
你进去拿到五十万
You go in and pick up that 500 grand.
我就变成通缉女匪
And I'm a wanted woman.
是的
Yes, you are. Mm.
妈  你来看这个
Hey, Mom, come and check this out.
等一下  宝贝  我马上到
One minute, sweetie. I'll be right there.
你去找格蕾茜  带她去安全的地方
Grab Gracie. Take her to safety.
分两路把车包围起来
Around the car on both sides.
-联调局  举起手来  -联调局
- FBI! Hands in the air! - FBI!
举起手来  站住
Hands in the air! Stop right there.
-所有人不许动  -妈
- Nobody move! - Mommy!
别动  别动
Don't move! Don't move!
举起手来  站在原地
Hands up! Stay right there.
别动  不许动
Don't move! Don't move!
老大  看到两件武器
Boss, see two weapons.
放艾米莉亚走
Let Amelia go.
你们想抓的是我
It's me you want.
你确定吗
You sure about that?
就我看来  这可不像绑匪和人质
From where I stand, it doesn't look like a captor and his hostage.
你似乎被骗了
Looks like a guy who's been played.
艾米莉亚并不爱你  彼得
Amelia doesn't love you, Peter.
他在骗你
He's lying.
别听他的
Don't listen to him.
我在说实话
Telling the truth.
那位柯林斯先生
Mr. Collins over there,
他才是为她牺牲了自己的人
he's the one who sacrificed himself for her.
是吧  大卫
Right, David?
当时她说  "你要是真的爱我  会跳的"
When she said, "If you really love me, you'll jump"?
你当时让我杀萨姆之前
That's what you said to me...
也是这么跟我说的
before you made me kill Sam.
彼得
Peter.
彼得  我永远不会背叛你
Peter, I would never betray you.
你的儿子和老公在自己家里被杀之前
And I bet your son and husband thought that
肯定也是这么想的
before they were shot dead in their own home.
别这么做  彼得
Don't do it, Peter.
你不希望事情无法收场
You don't want this to end the wrong way.
我来猜猜  艾米莉亚  这里有三本护照
Let me guess, Amelia, you got three passports over there:
一个给你  一个给格蕾茜  一个给大卫
one for you, one for Gracie, and one for David.
彼得从来不在你的最终计划里
Peter was never part of the end plan.
是大卫坚持的
David insisted.
如果我想让他帮忙  他必须跟着
If I wanted his help, he had to come along.
而且要带上枪
And to bring his gun
这样你可以在离开之前处理掉彼得
so you could take care of Peter before you left.
你说你想要我的
You said you wanted me.
你怎么能这么做
How could you do this?
格蕾茜是我们的女儿
Gracie's our daughter.
你唯一需要的男人  是你父亲
The only man you ever really needed was your father.
而他从来没有回应你
And he was never there for you.
这两个人只是被你利用
You just used those two.
你本打算拿着钱  带着女儿
You were gonna take the money and your daughter
直接逃走
and run.
对不对
Am I right?
双手放在背后
Put your hands behind your back.
手放在背后
Hands behind your back!
放在背后
Behind your back!
-放下武器  -不
- Drop the weapon! - No!
放下武器
Drop the weapon!
-放开我  -双手背后
- Get off me! - Hands behind your back!
别动了
Stop moving.
没事的  你看我  看着我
Gonna be okay. Look at me. Look at me. Look at me.
看着我  深呼吸
Look at me. Take some deep breaths, okay?
深呼吸  巴恩斯
Take a deep breath. Barnes?
尽快让急救人员赶过来
Get EMT out here as fast as they can.
收到  -你坚持住
Copy that. All right, stay with me.
我帮你压一下
I'm gonna put some pressure on it, all right?
你会没事的  知道吗
You're gonna be fine, okay?
坚持住  坚持
Stay with me. Stay with me.
-好了吗  -好
- All good? - Yeah.
用这个枕头吧
Here. Let's get this pillow.
你应该把腿抬高一点
You should elevate that bad boy.
我买了早餐
I brought breakfast.
还拿了你的药
And I got your pills.
选你喜欢的口味吧
Pick whatever flavor you want.
能量棒
克罗斯比
Crosby.
我肯定是落在店里了
Ah, must've left them at the store.
没事  我回去取吧
It's okay. I'll go back.
听说你会玩乐器
I heard you're a musician.
你听说对了
You heard right.
我很期待哪天听听你的演奏
Well, I'm looking forward to hearing you play sometime.
哈娜通常都会戴上耳机
Hana usually puts in her headphones.
很抱歉我忘拿你的药了
I am so sorry I left your pills.
你还好吗
You okay?
不太好
Not really.
我脑海中总是不停回放那时的画面
I just keep replaying what happened over and over.
哈娜  你不能这样想
Hana, you can't go there.
我们在上武器处理课的时候
We learn how to deal with this stuff all the time
学了很多次如何应对
in weapons retention class.
没错
Exactly.
他们怎么说的
And what do they say?
人们在被绑架之前
People sometimes go crazy
通常会很疯狂
when they're about to get arrested.
但你处理好了
But you handled it.
你的努力很可能阻止了老大中枪
And you probably prevented the boss from taking a bullet in the process.
所以你不能再自责了
So you gotta stop beating yourself up
告诉我  我能做什么
and tell me what I can do to help.
你饿吗
You hungry?
你不必这样照顾我
You don't have to play nurse.
但我愿意  来吧
But I want to. Come on.
我特别会做红肠煎蛋
I make a killer bologna omelet
或者加热千层面
or warm up lasagna.
还有芝士脆片
Cheese crisp?
把你的厨艺留给泽蒂吧
Save your cooking prowess for Zadie.
你之前说她在吃果汁断食
You said she was on a juice fast.
现实点吧
Let's be real.
我得三周不能下地
I'm gonna be off my feet for three weeks.
你有一份全职工作
You've got a full-time job.
泽蒂很好  但她不可靠
Zadie's great, but she's unreliable.
我要回达利安
I'm gonna go home to Darien,
找我爸妈
to my mom and dad.
确定吗
You sure?
我很确定
Yeah. I'm sure.
你可以跟泽蒂二人世界
Don't act like you're not gonna enjoy
少假装一副很遗憾的样子
having the whole place to yourself with Zadie.
你知道我肯定过得非常不开心
Ah, you know I'm gonna hate every minute of it.
晚点你能送我去达利安吗
Can you give me a ride to Darien later?
没问题
You got it.